- 我都招了 - 你他妈全在废话
- I told you… - You told me shit!
我跟他们不熟 只是在路上认识的
I barely knew those guys. I met 'em on the road.
你们有多少人
How many in your group?
不不不 别这样 兄弟
Uh, no, no… Come on, man.
有多少人
How many?!
30 30个人
Uh, 30… 30. 30 guys.
他们在哪儿
Where?
我发誓我真不知道
I don't know. I swear.
我们从不在一个地方待太久
We were never anyplace more than a night.
他们在侦察吗 准备在这里长住吗
Scouting? Planning on staying local?
我不知道 他们把我抛下了
I… I don't know. They… they left me behind.
- 你被人揭过伤疤吗 - 拜托
- Did you ever pick off a scab? - Come on, man!
- 我在努力配合 - 刚开始可不够配合
- I'm-I'm trying to cooperate. - Start real slow at first.
- 不是 - 你迟早都要坦白
- No. - Sooner or later, you've just gotta rip it off.
好吧 我说
Okay. Okay.
他们有武器
They have weapons…
重装备 自动步枪
Heavy stuff, automatics.
但我什么也没做
But I didn't do anything.
你们的人试图射杀我们 夺走农场
Your boys shot at my boys, tried to take this farm.
而你只是跟着打酱油吗
You just went along for the ride?
你想说自己是无辜的吗
You're trying to tell me you're innocent?
是的
Yes!
那些人收留了我
These… these people took me in.
不只是男人 他们有一群人
Not just guys… a whole group of 'em.
有男有女
Men and women,
还有孩子 就和你们一样
kids too… just like you people.
我以为跟他们一起生存希望能大一点
Thought I'd have a better chance with them, you know?
但是
But…
我们出去 寻找补给
We go out, scavenge…
就几个男人
Just the men.
有一天晚上 我们找到了块野营地
One night, we… we found this little campsite.
一个男人和他的两个女儿
A man and his two daughters…
只是豆蔻少女
Teenagers, you know?
非常年轻 非常可爱
Real young. Real cute.
她们的父亲只能眼睁睁看着他们…
Their daddy had to watch while these guys… they…
那群人都不愿给他个痛快
and they didn't even kill him afterwards.
就让他这么看着
They just… they just made him watch.
目睹他女儿被
as his daughters…
就这么把他扔那
They just-just… just left him there.
但我没碰那两个女孩
No, but-but… but I didn't touch those girls.
我发誓我没有
No, I swear I didn't to…
求求你
Please.
求你 请相信我
Please. You gotta believe me, man.
我不是那种人
I'm not like that.
我不是那样的
I ain't like that.
求你了 你一定得相信我
Please. Please, you gotta believe me.
《行尸走肉》
那么你打算怎么办
So, what you gonna do?
知道计划能让我们安心些
We'd all feel better if we knew the plan.
- 有计划吗 - 我们要把他留在这儿吗
- Is there a plan? - We gonna keep him here?
很快就能知道答案了
We'll know soon enough.
他们有一群人 30个人
Boy there's got a gang, 30 men.
他们有重武装
They have heavy artillery.
看上去可不是什么善类
and they ain't looking to make friends.
他们如果来到这里 我们就死定了
They roll through here, our boys are dead.
而女人们会生不如死
And our women, they're gonna… they're gonna wish they were.
你对他做了什么
What did you do?
聊了会天
Had a little chat.
谁都不许接近那个人
No one goes near this guy.
瑞克 你打算怎么做
Rick, what are you gonna do?
我们没有选择 他是个威胁
We have no choice. He's a threat.
我们不能留下后患
We have to eliminate the threat.
你打算就这么杀了他
You're just gonna kill him?
已经决定了 我今天就做
It's settled. I'll do it today.
你不能这么做
You can't do this.
你内心其实是不想的 我知道
You don't wanna do this. I know you don't.
我考虑了一整晚
I thought about it all night.
知道了新的信息 我觉得这已无法避免
Knowing what we know now, I don't see a way out of it.
但你不能就这么决定他人的生死
But you can't just decide on your own to take someone's life.
大家看上去都很支持
The group seemed supportive.
那是因为你没给他们机会提出异议
What, because they didn't speak back? You didn't let 'em.
必须要有一个过程
There's gotta be a… a process.
什么过程 我们不可能搞个审判
And what would that be? We can't call witnesses,
请证人出庭
Go before a judge.
所以他就这么被臆断为有罪
So he's automatically guilty by association.
然后判处死刑
And sentenced to death?
他只是个孩子
He's just a kid.
- 让我跟大家再谈谈 - 我们不能
- Gimme some time to talk to everyone… - We can't…
- 想想有没有其他办法 - 不行
- …try to figure out another way… - No,
我们不能慢慢来
we can't drag this out!
大家都很害怕
People are scared.
那就更需要花时间认真商讨
Which is why they need time to discuss this.
不 不 他们需要被保护好
No, no, no, they need to be safe.
- 这是我的职责 - 你想想你的儿子
- I owe 'em that. - You think about your son!
想想你给他做的榜样
The message that you're giving him…
冲动行事 不计后果
shoot first, think later.
我只求一天时间 和大家谈谈
I'm asking for one day to talk to everybody.
你可以答应的 想想卡尔
You can give me that. Think-think about Carl.
我在想
I am.
我们日落时集合 做出最终决定
We reconvene at sunset, then what happens, happens.
- 帮我个忙 - 你动过武器袋吗
- I need a favor. - Did you move the gun bag?
是啊
Yeah.
我需要你去守着兰德尔
I need you to guard Randall,
保护他安全
Protect him.
- 为什么 - 瑞克给了我时间和大家谈谈
- Why? - Rick's giving me time to talk to the others,
我想让他们恢复理智
try and talk some sense into them.
如果让肖恩知道了
But if Shane finds out…
你觉得他会直接杀了那家伙
You think he'd just shoot the guy himself?
你知道杀这男孩肯定是他的主意
You know killing the boy had to be his idea.
你站在他那边吗
Are you with him on this?
他是个威胁
He's a threat.
别告诉我这就是全部弹药
Tell me this isn't all the ammo.
你是个民事律师
You're a civil rights lawyer.
- 曾是 - 你靠唇枪舌辩
- Was. - You fight with words,
以思想为武器
the power of ideas.
用枪是他的风格
Using a-a gun, that's his way.
你真要和我吵这个
You really want to debate about saving a guy.
放走一个会带人来杀我们的家伙
Who will lead his buddies right to our door?
这是文明社会的道德准则
That's what a civilized society does.
谁说这不再是文明社会了
Who says we're civilized anymore?
不对 我们熟知的那个世界已经消失
No, the world we knew is gone,
但是否保留人性善心
But keeping our humanity?
仍是我们的选择
That's a choice.
我会帮你看着囚犯
I'll watch your prisoner.
但这并不代表我认同你
But not because I think you're right.
有人吗
Hello?
喂
Hey.
我能喝点水么
Can I get some water?
求你了
Please?
我渴死了
I'm very thirsty.
他们会杀了我 对吗
They're gonna kill me, right?
听说他是个小孩
So he's a kid?
他不只是个小孩 他
He ain't a kid. Just…
那只是一种比喻
That's a figure of speech.
- 我能见见他吗 - 不行
- Can I see him? - No.
听着 这是大人的事 好吗
Look, man, this is… this is grown-up stuff, all right?
你 你让我们来处理
You just… you just let us handle this.
是戴尔吧
Dale, huh?
怎么 派你来做临终看护人
What, he put you on death watch?
我问你 如果我现在要进去
Let me ask you something… say I wanted to go in there right now.
我只是想解决这事 你会阻止我吗
And I just wanted to take care of this, you gonna stop me? Hmm?
- 我老师很好哦 - 是啊
- I had a good teacher. - Yeah.
所以呢
So what?
你被戴尔的悲情剧场打动了
You buy into Dale's sob story?
我告诉他这事我站你这边
I told him I was with you on this.
但你还是帮着他 对吧
Mmm… You're just still here for him, huh?
真可爱
That's cute.
你清楚形势吧
You see what's happening, don't you?
这伙人不会同意的
These guys ain't gonna go through with this.
我告诉你 他们想
I'm telling you, they gonna…
他们会临阵退缩 如果真这样
they gonna pussy out. And if they do,
我们麻烦就大了
we gonna have a big problem on our hands.
我问你
Let me ask you something…
每次我们遇到麻烦
every time we have a problem around here,
你觉得是谁造成的
Who do you think's behind it?
有人觉得是你
Some might say you.
才怪 没人听我的
Nah. No one listens to me.
我觉得是那几个定规矩的人
I say it's the guys that make up the rules,
那几个自以为什么都懂的家伙
the boys that always have all the answers,
哪怕事实证明他们是错的
even though their answers always prove wrong.
那你要怎么办 瑞克是头儿
So what are you gonna do? Rick's the leader of this group,
- 农场又是赫谢尔的 - 也许得改变现状了
- It's Hershel's farm. - Maybe we oughta change that.
啥 你要缴走他们的枪
What, are you gonna lock 'em in a room.
把他们锁起来吗
and take their guns?
我不知道 那样形势可能会失控
I don't know. That could get out of hand.
不会的 我不会让事情失控的
No, no, it won't. Okay? I won't let it.
听着 我不想让任何人受伤 好吗
Listen, I don't… I don't want anybody to get hurt, okay?
瑞克是我的朋友 我也不讨厌赫谢尔
Rick's my friend, Hershel… he's all right by me.
- 那戴尔呢 - 戴尔虽然很多嘴
- And Dale? - Dale got a big mouth,
但他不会伤人
but he's harmless.
听着 我只是想睡个安稳觉
Look, I just… I wanna know what it's like to sleep.
不想整天提心吊胆 这不就是
without keeping one eye open. Ain't that…
这不就是大家的愿望吗
ain't that what we all want?
主动权在他们手里 或许我是错的
Hey, ball's in their court. Maybe I'm wrong.
又或许我只是小题大做
Maybe I'm getting all worked up over nothing.
帽子真帅
That's a sweet hat.
我叫兰德尔 你叫什么
I'm Randall. What's your name?
那警官是你爸爸吗
The sheriff guy… that your dad?
我喜欢他
I like him.
真的 他是个好人 我看得出来
Yeah, he's a good guy. I can tell.
你妈妈也在这儿吗
Your mom out here too?
你真幸运 家人都还在
You're… you're lucky you still got your family.
我失去家人了
I lost mine.
听着 我不知道他们怎么说我
Hey, I… I don't know what people been saying about me,
但我什么坏事都没做 我发誓
but I didn't do nothing. I swear.
你爸本来都要放我走的
Your dad was gonna let me go.
可他和他朋友打了起来
till his friend started fighting with him.
当时情况很糟 我有点着急
It got pretty bad. I… I was kinda worried.
我们的营地物资充沛
My camp, we got lots of supplies.
你帮我 我就带你们一伙人去见我的人
You help me, I'll take you and your folks back to my people.
我们会照顾好你们的
We'll take good care of you.
保护你们 只要你
Keep you safe. Just gotta…
只要你帮我逃出去 好吗
just gotta help me get out of here, okay?
只要帮我打开锁 或者找找钥匙好吗
Just help me pick these locks or find the key, okay?
帮帮我吧 求你了
Come on, please?
求你了
Please?
你在这儿干什么 你跟他说啥了
What the hell are you doing in here? What did you say to him?
- 你跟他说啥了 - 我啥也没说
- What did you say to him, huh? - I didn't say nothing.
老子告诉你
Let me tell you something…
- 老子马上就毙了你 - 好啦 肖恩 别这样
- I will shoot you where you sit. - Okay Shane, not now.
- 张开嘴 张开嘴 - 肖恩 别这样
- Open your mouth. Open your mouth. - Shane.
让你丫多嘴 让你丫多嘴
You like talking, man? You like talking?!
住手
Back off!
小兔崽子快出去 快走
Get your ass out this door. Let's go.
- 你搞什么鬼 - 求你别告诉我爸妈
- The hell you doing? - Please don't tell my parents.
卡尔 这不好玩 你可能会受伤的
Carl, that ain't cool, man. You could've gotten hurt in there.
- 我能管好自己 - 我告诉你
- I can handle myself. - Let me tell you something…
别再靠近他 听见没有
You do not go near him again. Do you hear me?
- 妈的 - 你不会告诉我爸妈吧
- Damn it. - You won't tell my parents, will you?
卡尔
Carl, man,
这不是闯祸的问题
this isn't about getting in trouble, okay?
像他这种人 什么话都可能说
A guy like that, he will say anything to you.
他会让你可怜他
He'll try to make you feel sorry for him.
他会让你降低警惕
He'll try to make you get your guard down.
你要是降低警惕 就要死人了
You let your guard down out here, people die.
现在
Now, just…
帮我个忙 去把你妈找来 快去
Do me a favor, man… go find your mom. Go on.
卡尔
Carl,
别再干傻事了
quit trying to get yourself killed, man.
我之所以跑到这儿
The whole point of me coming up here is.
就是避开你们
to get away from you people.
光这样可躲不开我们
Gonna take more than that.
卡萝尔让你来的吗
Carol send you?
不只卡萝尔关心你
Carol's not the only one that's concerned about you,
和你在队伍里的角色
your new role in the group.
我可不需要心理辅导
Oh, man, I don't need my head shrunk.
队伍早就散了
This group's broken.
我还是管好自己吧
I'm better off fending for myself.
你好像不在乎啊
You act like you don't care.
是啊 因为我是不在乎
Yeah, it's 'cause I don't.
所以你不在乎兰德尔的死活吗
So live or die, you don't care what happens to Randall?
不在乎
Nope.
那你为什么不和我一起
Then why not stand with me,
试着去救那孩子的命
try to save the kid's life,
既然一切都无所谓的话
if it really doesn't matter one way or the other?
你让自己显得像个绝望的混蛋
Didn't peg you for a desperate son of a bitch.
你的意见会让事情改变
Your opinion makes a difference.
老头 没人会来找我帮忙
Man, ain't nobody looking at me for nothing.
卡萝尔会 我会 现在就是
Carol is, and I am. Right now.
而你显然能说服瑞克
And you obviously… you have Rick's ear.
瑞克只听肖恩的 随他去吧
Rick just looks to Shane. Let him.
你在乎索菲亚
You cared about what happened to Sofia.
在乎她对大伙的意义
Cared what it meant to the group.
拷问人 那不是你的作风
Torturing people? That isn't you.
你是个正直的人
You're a decent man.
瑞克也是
So is Rick.
肖恩 他不同
Shane… he's different.
为什么 因为他杀了奥蒂斯吗
Why's that? 'cause he killed Otis?
他告诉你的吗
He tell you that?
他撒了谎
He told some story…
说奥蒂斯掩护他 救了他
how Otis covered him, saved his ass.
他却是带着那死人的枪回来的
He showed up with the dead guy's gun.
瑞克不是傻子
Rick ain't stupid.
他要是没识破 那是因为他不想识破
If he didn't figure that out, it's 'cause he didn't wanna.
就像我说的 队伍早散了
It's like I said… group's broken.
宝贝 你爸呢
Baby, where's your daddy?
- 他在那儿 - 好的
- He's up there. - All right.
那个…
So, uh…
夜晚越来越冷 我们又暴露在外
The nights are getting colder and we're pretty exposed.
- 我在想… - 也许我们可以清理一下这里
- I was thinking… - Maybe we could clear this place out,
在这边设个岗哨
Station lookouts up here.
也许我们可以和赫谢尔谈谈
Or we could talk to Hershel.
让我们进屋住去
about staying in the house.
- 是啊 - 好的
- Yeah. - All right.
这样做是最好的吗
Is that really the best way to do this?
非要绞死他吗
To… string him up?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
我是头一回
It's my first time.
我知道你反对死刑 但是
Look, I know how you feel about the death penalty, but…
我也知道世道变了
And I know the world has changed.
经历了这一切
After everything that's happened,
你和肖恩达成了共识
You and Shane agree on this.
那你赞同这个决定吗
So you support this decision?
如果你觉得这样最好的话
If you think it's best.
你一直没跟我说
You never did tell me.
你和肖恩在路上怎么了
what happened on the road with you and Shane.
他不会再找麻烦了
He won't be a problem anymore.
我们会在天堂和索菲亚重逢的
You know, we'll see Sophia again in heaven some day.
她去了更好的地方
She's in a better place.
才不是呢
No, she's not.
天堂只是骗人的
Heaven is just another lie,
如果你相信 你就是傻子
and if you believe it, you're an idiot.
你们得管管你家孩子了
You need to control that boy.
卡尔 怎么了
Carl? What happened?
他大不敬
He's disrespectful.
他说啥了
Did he say something?
说了些对不起索菲亚的话
Something cruel about Sofia.
- 我们会管教他的 没关系 - 有关系
- We'll figure it out. It's okay. I… - It's not okay.
我会 我会找他谈谈
I'll have… I'll have a talk with him.
瞧 我们会
See? We'll… we'll…
我们会管教他的 你冷静点 我才能
We'll deal with it. If you can calm down, so that I can…
- 别叫我冷静 - 不 我不是…
- Don't tell me to calm down! - No, I… I don't…
我不需要你可怜我 大家要么躲着我
I don't need you to patronize me. Everyone either avoids me.
要么就当我是疯子
or they treat me like I'm crazy.
我是失去了女儿 可我没失去理智
I lost my daughter. I didn't lose my mind!
卡尔 过来
Carl, come over here.
你冲卡萝尔顶嘴了吗
Did you talk back to Carol?
- 没有 - 她说你有
- No. - She says you did.
你不能这么跟别人说话
You can't talk back to people like that.
我说 相信天堂的人是傻子
I said it's stupid to believe in heaven.
本来就是
'cause it is.
你再仔细想一下
Well, just think about that for a minute.
她刚失去了女儿
She just lost her daughter.
她希望她女儿在另外一个地方快乐地活着
She wants to believe she's still alive in some way.
- 但是她 - 别
- But she… - Don't…
少说话 多思考
Don't talk. Think.
这是经验之谈
It's a good rule of thumb for life.
妈妈总是希望你能多说话
Mom always wants you to talk more.
不要改变话题
Don't change the subject.
你应该向卡萝尔道歉
You owe Carol an apology.
你犯了错 要想办法弥补
You made a mistake. Fix it.
这就是你要杀那个人的原因吗
Is that why you're gonna kill that guy?
弥补自己犯下的错误
Fixing your mistake?
那不一样
That's different.
你打算怎么做 把他吊死在谷仓里吗
How are you gonna do it? Are you gonna hang him in the barn?
你只需要处理好
You just think about how.
自己和卡萝尔的事情就行了
you're gonna make things right with Carol.
少说话 多思考
Don't talk. Think.
- 明白吗 - 明白
- You got it? - Yeah.
- 怎么了 - 一群牛挤倒栅栏跑了
- What happened? - A dozen steer busted through the fence.
为了跑掉的牛吵了一早晨
Been wrangling the runaways all morning.
你不是来和我讨论牛的事吧
But you're not here to talk cattle.
- 那个孩子 - 那个犯人
- The boy. - The prisoner.
- 兰德尔 - 我不想知道
- Randall. - I don't want to know.
大家会决定他的命运
I'm told they're deciding his fate.
瑞克负责就行了
I'll leave it with Rick.
但这是你的家
But this is your home.
我只想让他离我女儿们远远的
I want him away from my girls.
我不在乎怎么做到
I don't care how.
- 那是赤裸裸的处刑 - 我不想知道
- It's an execution. - I don't want to know.
但是你不能袖手旁观
But you can't stand by the sidelines.
你是有信念的人 你
You're a man with convictions. You…
给你说实话吧 我以前是
To tell you the truth, I was.
至少我以为我是
Or at least I thought I was.
但是我犯了太多错
But I've made too many mistakes.
在你做决定之前
Would you at least talk with Randall.
你至少应该和兰德尔谈谈吧
before making up your mind?
不 让瑞克全权负责吧
No. I'll leave it with Rick.
怎么了 戴尔
What's up, Dale?
我想让你改个主意
I wanna change your mind.
你是认真的吗
what, you serious?
我知道咱们俩不可能看法完全一致
I know you and I will never see eye to eye on much…
你说得真轻描淡写
Say that's the understatement of the year, huh?
但是
But, uh,
- 你哪也不去 - 对
- you're not going anywhere… - Nope.
- 我也哪都不去 - 好的
- …and I'm not going anywhere. - Okay.
那我们像男人一样说说这事
So let's talk about this like men.
好的
Okay.
你觉得我们没有身处危险之中吗 戴尔
You deny we're in danger, Dale?
不是 但是我们人多势众
No, but there's a dozen of us,
而他势单力薄
one of him.
他们有30个人
There's 30 of them.
杀掉他也改变不了这个事实
Killing him doesn't change that…
- 不会 - 但是会改变我们
- No. - But it changes us.
你
You…
你有胆量 戴尔
you got balls, Dale.
可以这么说
I'm gonna give you that.
现在
Now…
我告诉你 等会大家讨论这个问题
I'll tell you what… in a little bit, when y'all gather,
你会表达自己的观点
you're gonna talk about this.
如果你说服了大家放过这个家伙
If you've convinced them to keep this guy alive,
我没有意见 行吗
then I ain't gonna say a damn word about it, okay?
但是我直接告诉你
But I'm telling you now, man to man,
你错了
you're wrong.
如果这个家伙日后杀了人
And when this guy kills somebody,
我什么都不用说
I ain't gonna need to say anything,
因为那笔血账一定会算在你头上
because that blood… that's gonna be on you.
你错了 戴尔 大错特错
You're wrong about this, Dale. You're dead wrong.
小虫小虫快飞吧 快快飞回你的家
Doodlebug, doodlebug, go away home.
小虫虫
Doodlebug.
小虫小虫快飞吧 快快飞回你的家
Doodlebug, doodlebug, go away home.
- 她怎么样了 - 今天看起来精神不错
- How is she? - She seems to be in good spirits today.
是不是呀 小虫虫
Aren't you, doodlebug?
如果需要我的话就尽管说
Well, let me know if I can do anything.
你家从哪来啊
Where's your family from?
密歇根
Michigan.
在那之前是在韩国
But, uh, before that, Korea.
移民建造了这个国家
Immigrants built this country.
永远不要忘了这一点
Never forget that.
我们家是从爱尔兰来的
Our family came from Ireland.
玛姬·格林 我感觉也是
Maggie Greene… I kinda figured.
我祖父把这个从家乡带过来
My grandfather brought this over from the old country.
传给了我爸爸 又传给了我
He passed it on to my father, who passed it on to me.
有一天我把它当了买酒喝
I pawned it to pay for a night of drinking.
我不记得是哪天了
I no longer remember.
你把它买了回来
You bought it back.
我第二任妻子买回来的 约瑟芬
My late wife did… Josephine,
玛姬的母亲
Maggie's mother.
几年之后我戒了酒
She gave it back years later.
她又还给了我
when I sobered up.
我的约瑟芬 她是个好女人
She was a good woman, my Jo.
玛姬很像她
Maggie's a lot like her.
我们在那个酒吧的时候 还有回来之后
When we were in that bar and afterwards,
我想了很多
I thought about a lot of things.
总有一天你也会成为父亲 你会明白的
You become a father someday, you'll understand.
没有人能配得上自己的小女儿
No man is good enough for your little girl…
直到那个人出现
until one is.
送给你 别让我改变对你的印象
You own it now, before I change my mind about you.
谢谢
Thanks.
到时间了
It's almost time.
我知道对于你来说这不容易
I know this isn't easy for you.
对谁来说都不容易
It isn't easy for anyone.
但是我仔细想过了
But I thought it through.
我做了决定
I made the call.
我准备好了
I'm ready to do this.
你不必亲自动手
You don't have to be the one to do it…
肖恩 达里尔都可以
Shane, Daryl.
不 就得是我
Yeah, it has to be me.
我把他带回来的 也许我不应该这么做
I brought him back here. Maybe I shouldn't have.
我必须确保这些人的安全
I gotta keep these people safe.
这就是我要做的
That is what I'm gonna do.
那戴尔怎么办
What about Dale?
他一直在努力说服大家
He's got an uphill battle.
- 你说过你支持我 - 是的
- You said you support me. - I do.
但是你不认为这是正确的决定
But you didn't say you think I'm making the right call.
这是正确的决定
This is the right call.
集合吧
Let's gather up.
快来 卡尔 你去和吉米呆在一起
Come on, Carl. I want you to stay with Jimmy.
但是我想参加
But I wanna listen.
这次不行 快去吧
Hm-mmm, not this time. Come on.
我们怎么做 投票表决吗
So how do we do this? Just take a vote?
全票通过才行吗
Does it have to be unanimous?
少数服从多数怎么样
How about majority rules?
我们先看看大家的意见
Well, let's… let's just see where everybody stands,
然后再做决定
then we can talk through the options.
我的意见是
Well, where I sit,
只有一个办法
there's only one way to move forward.
杀了他 对吗
Killing him, right?
我们根本不用投票
I mean, why even bother to even take a vote?
大家的意见显而易见
It's clear which way the wind's blowing.
如果有人认为我们应该放过他
Well, if people believe we should spare him,
我想知道是谁
I wanna know.
我可以告诉你只有一小波人
Well, I can tell you it's a small group…
可能只有我和格伦
Maybe just me and Glenn.
听着
Look, I…
我知道在很多事情上你的看法都很对
I think you're pretty much right about everything,
一直都是 但是这次
all the time, but this…
他们都让你害怕了
They've got you scared.
他不是我们中的一员
He's not one of us.
我们已经失去了很多人
And we've… we've lost too many people already.
你呢 你同意吗
How about you? Do you agree with this?
我们不能继续关着他吗
Couldn't we continue keeping him prisoner?
那又多了一张嘴吃饭
Just another mouth to feed.
这个冬天我们可能粮食减产
It may be a lean winter.
我们可以更好地规划一下
We could ration better.
他可能有利用价值
Well, he could be an asset.
给他个机会让他证明一下
Give him a chance to prove himself.
让他去干活吗
Put him to work?
我们不能让他随意走动
We're not letting him walk around.
我们可以找个人看着他
We could put an escort on him.
谁愿意去呢
Who wants to volunteer for that duty?
- 我去 - 我认为我们谁都不应该
- I will. - I don't think any of us should be walking around.
- 和他呆在一起 - 他说得对
- with this guy. - He's right.
他绑起来我才觉得安全
I wouldn't feel safe unless he was tied up.
我们怎么能真的给他上脚镣
We can't exactly put chains around his ankles,
判他去做苦力
sentence him to hard labor.
听着 如果我们让他加入我们
Look, say we let him join us, right?
也许他能帮忙 也许他人很好
Maybe he's helpful, maybe he's nice.
我们会放松警惕 他就可能逃跑
We let our guard down and maybe he runs off,
带回来30个他们的人
brings back his 30 men.
所以杀他的原因
So the answer is to kill him.
是去阻止他也许永远不会犯的罪行
to prevent a crime that he may never even attempt?
如果我们这样做
If we do this,
就代表了没有希望
we're saying there's no hope.
没有法律 没有文明
Rule of law is dead. There is no civilization.
我的上帝啊
Oh, my god.
你能开车把他送的更远一点吗
Could you drive him further out?
像之前计划的一样丢下他
Leave him like you planned?
你这次都差点没能回来
You barely came back this time.
到处都是行尸 你会被干掉
There are walkers. You could break down.
- 你会迷路 - 或者中埋伏
- Y-you could get lost. - Or get ambushed.
他们说的对 我们不能让自己人冒险
They're right. We should not put our own people at risk.
如果真要杀他
If you go through with it,
你准备怎么做
How would you do it?
他死前会受苦吗
Would he suffer?
我们可以吊死他 勒断他的脖子
We could hang him, right? Just snap his neck.
我考虑过那个
I thought about that.
用枪也许更人性点
Shooting may be more humane.
尸体怎么处理
And what about the body?
- 我们埋他吗 - 等等 等等
- Do we bury him? - Hold on, hold on!
你们说得好像已经决定了一样
You're talking about this like it's already decided.
已经商量了一整天 没有什么实质进展
You've been talking all day, going around in circles.
你还准备继续浪费时间吗
You just wanna go around in circles again?
这是一个年轻人的生命
This is a young man's life,
我们怎么能只谈5分钟呢
and it is worth more than a five-minute conversation!
现在都变成这样了吗
Is this what it's come to?
我们不知道该拿他怎么办 就直接杀了他
We kill someone because we can't decide what else to do with him?
你救了他
You saved him.
但看看我们
and now look at us.
他被折磨 还会被处死
He's been tortured. He's gonna be executed.
我们比那些我们害怕的家伙能好多少
How are we any better than those people that we're so afraid of?
我们都知道这是必须做的
We all know what needs to be done.
不 戴尔是对的
No, Dale is right.
我们不能草率决定
We can't leave any stone unturned here.
- 我们有负责 - 还有别的办法吗
- We have a responsibility… - so what's the other solution?
让瑞克说完
Let Rick finish.
我们到现在还没想出一个可行的办法
We haven't come up with a single viable option yet.
- 我希望我们可以 - 那就再想想啊
- I wish we could. - So let's work on it!
- 我们会的 - 别说了 别说了
- We are. - Stop it. Just stop it.
我受够所有人的争论和争吵了
I'm sick of everybody arguing and fighting.
我不想这样
I didn't ask for this.
你不能让我们在这种事上做选择
You can't ask us to decide something like this.
你们决定吧 你们俩谁都行
Please decide… either of you, both of you…
但别把我算进去
but leave me out.
不为他辩护
Not speaking out.
和亲手杀了他
or killing him yourself…
没有什么区别
there's no difference.
好了 够了
All right, that's enough.
任何人都有机会
Anybody who wants the floor.
在我们做出最终决定前
before we make a final decision.
提出异议
has the chance.
你曾经说过我们不会杀活人
You once said that we don't kill the living.
那是在别人想杀我们之前
Well, that was before the living tried to kill us.
你难道不明白吗 如果我们这么做
But don't you see? If we do this,
我们自己
the people that we were…
和我们所认知的世界将会崩塌
the world that we knew is dead.
这个新世界很丑陋
And this new world is ugly.
很…
It's…
残酷 是适者生存的世界
harsh. It's… it's survival of the fittest.
我不愿活在那样的世界中
And that's a world I don't wanna live in,
我相信你们也不愿意
and I don't… and I don't believe that any of you do.
我做不到
I can't.
求你们了
Please.
就让我们做对的事情吧
Let's just do what's right.
难道没有人支持我吗
Isn't there anybody else who's gonna stand with me?
他说的对
He's right.
我们应该想想另外的办法
We should try to find another way.
还有人吗
Anybody else?
你们是不是还准备观看
Are y'all gonna watch, too?
不 你们会躲在帐篷里
No, you'll go hide your heads in your tents.
试着忘记我们杀了一个活生生的人
and try to forget that we're slaughtering a human being.
我不想参与
I won't be a party to it.
这个队伍确实散了
This group is broken.
等等 等等
Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
Wait, wait, wait!
- 啊 - 把他放在那儿
- Ah. - Put him there.
- 嘿嘿 - 很快会结束的
- hey-hey! - It's all gonna be over soon.
什么会很快结束
What? What's gonna be over soon?
- 放松 - 不 不 不
- Relax. - Hey… hey. No, no, no, no.
不
No.
不 不 不
Oh, no… no.
你想站着还是跪着
Would you like to stand or kneel?
不 求你了
Oh, no, please.
求你了…
Ple… ah-ah-ah.
你有什么遗言吗
Do you have any final words?
不 求你了
No, please.
求你了不要 不要
Please don't. Don't.
下手 爸爸
Do it, dad.
下手啊
Do it.
开什么玩笑 我怎么给你说的
Are you kidding me? What'd I say to you?
我怎么给你说的
What did I say to you?
把他带走
Take him away.
- 站起来 - 啊啊
- Get up. - Ah. Ah.
我们暂时把他关起来
We're keeping him in custody, for now.
我去找戴尔
I'm gonna find Dale.
卡尔 进屋去
Carl, go inside.
现在
Now, please.
他跟我们来的
He followed us.
他想看着
He wanted to watch.
- 我不能… - 没关系
- I couldn't… - That's okay.
没关系
That's okay.
- 看着卡尔 - 宝贝
- Get Carl. - Baby.
- 发生了什么 - 过来 过来
- What happened? - Come here. Come here.
T仔 快去拿把猎枪
T-dog, get a shotgun now!
我要你进屋去 锁上门
I want you to go in the house, I want you to lock the door.
- 我要你待在房子里 - 好的 好的
- and I want you to stay inside. - Okay, okay.
那是什么
what was that?
- 发生了什么 - 我不知道 快去
- What happened? - I don't know… go!
不
No!
戴尔
Dale!
救命啊 在这边
Help! Over here!
- 救命啊 快点 坚持住老兄 - 是谁
- Help! Run! Hang in there, buddy. - Who is it?
我的上帝啊
Oh, my god. Oh, god.
- 瑞克 - 好了 把注意力集中在我声音上
- Rick! - All right, just listen to my voice.
听我的声音好吗 听我的声音
Listen to me, all right? Just listen to me.
好的 坚持住 叫赫谢尔来
Okay, hold on now. Get Hershel!
- 他需要输血 必须立刻处理 - 坚持住 戴尔
- He needs blood. We gotta operate now. - Hang on, Dale.
坚持住
Hang on.
听我说
Listen to me.
注意力集中在我声音上
Come on… okay, just listen to my voice.
好了 快点 赫谢尔 我们需要赫谢尔
All right, please. Hershel! We need Hershel!
- 看着我 - 戴尔 我们会帮你的 有我们在
- Look at me. - Dale, we're gonna help. We're here.
- 一定要坚持住 - 怎么回事
- Just hold on… hold on. - What happened?
- 我们能做什么 - 戴尔 一切都会好起来的
- What can we do? - Dale, it's gonna be okay.
- 我们能转移他吗 - 他没法承受颠簸
- Can we move him? - He won't make the trip.
你必须在这里治疗
You have to do the operation here.
- 格伦 回屋子去拿… - 瑞克
- Glenn, get back to the house… - Rick.
不
No!
上帝啊
Oh, god.
他很痛苦
He's suffering.
做点什么
Do something!
快点
Come on.
上帝啊
Oh, god.
对不起 老兄
Sorry, brother.